Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mr. Ryu, standby okay!
Good!
Amuro, standby for docking.
Ready?
I'm going in, Mr. Ryu!
5... 4...
3... 2... 1...
Laser searcher synchronized.
5... 4...
Gundam B Parts released!
Core Change! Docking, go!
The young crew had survived thus far
by working together as one.
But selfishness and frustration...
...had created an uncomfortable tension
among the crew members.
However...
...the enemy was bearing down on them
regardless of the youths' problems.
Hand-to-Hand Combat
The decryption isn't wrong, is it...?
No. It says,
"Stay put until Odessa Day."
I checked many times.
Ramba Ral, was it?
Yes.
He'll get us at this rate.
I know, but Marker and Oscar
need to rest.
Right. Those two may be
the hardest workers in the crew.
Can I join you?
Aren't you mending the kids' clothes?
I'm all finished.
You're such a busy bee.
Are you eating at all?!
Close the door. I might escape.
Don't say things like that!
That Ramba Ral guy
will definitely come after us.
Even without his Zakus and Gouf...
he'll be all the more determined. For sure.
So let 'em come.
I'll pilot the Gundam then.
And what would you do?
I think I might leave the White Base.
Are you serious?!
Yeah! Why shouldn't I?!
No one feels comfortable with me anymore.
Why, you!
You put all your strength into that punch,
didn't you, Mr. Ryu.
There was a time when
Ms. Matilda said that you...
...might be some kind of an Esper.
I thought it was a reasonable thing
to say about you.
It's about time you stopped sulking!
Quoting Ms. Matilda?
Try lecturing me with your own words.
Let's go, Fraw Bow.
Right.
Does he really think one angry man
is enough to change a person?
May I come in?
Sure.
Excuse me.
It's about Amuro, but...
...Mr. Bright, you have no intention
of taking him off the Gundam, right?
Why do you think that?
The reason you put him in the brig...
...is to make Amuro think about what he did.
In other words, you're still counting on him.
That's right.
But Bright, you were the one
who wanted to remove him.
Why...?
Amuro could have taken the Gundam
and defected to Zeon.
I puzzled over why he didn't do that.
And as a result, I...
Have hopes for him?
Right.
Amuro only came back because
he was momentarily homesick.
But, you know, he's almost
where we need him to be.
Right, Ryu?
Is this about Amuro?
Hmm...
I think he'll be all right.
Lieutenant Ral,
a message from Admiral Dozle.
It was relayed by Captain M'Quve.
This is good news, Hamon.
They're sending us 3 ground type
Dom mobile suits.
Doms?
You mean those heavy mobile suits?
Hamon, we're moving out.
We attack the Trojan Horse
as soon as we receive those Doms.
Under the command of Kycilia Zabi,
Captain M'Quve's unit...
...controls the world's largest
mineral resources.
This is M'Quve's main base.
Ramba Ral knows too much
about my mining activities here.
These mines will be useful when
Lady Kycilia rules Zeon.
Even Lord Gihren
cannot realize the truth.
Yes, sir.
You know what to do next?
But... we're sabotaging a request
from the Admiral.
Don't worry.
Ramba Ral won't see it that way.
Yes, sir!
Ryu! Wake up! Ryu!
Ryu! Hayato and the others just left!
What's that, Ms. Sayla?
Hayato, Kai, Howard, and Maximilian
just took off! Can you follow them?
Sure, I'll get right on it!
I can't believe this!
Everyone's acting so selfishly!
Thanks, Ryu!
Leave it to me! I'll bring them back
even if I've gotta knock some sense into them!
Ryu! I want to go too! Take me with you!
I'll be back soon!
Hayato is pretty forthright,
in his own way.
Have we really been paying
too much attention to Amuro?
Everyone's overlooking one crucial thing.
Overlooking what?
When Amuro was away,
I felt very uneasy as commander.
Uneasy...
I think you've brought us a lot of luck...
...but without Amuro...
...I felt an incredible uneasiness
that I've never felt before.
What could it be?
- Point A13. There's no mistake?
- No, sir.
30 minutes have passed.
Look, dear. A light!
That belongs to one of M'Quve's men.
The Doms aren't coming?!
Yes. It is very unfortunate.
M'Quve's forces couldn't provide
cover in time.
The supply ship was destroyed just before
entering Central Asia. The Doms were...
Tell Lord M'Quve that I, Ramba Ral...
...will carry out my mission,
even if it's with my bare hands.
Yes, sir!
Thank you.
Excuse me.
I see.
I guess that's what they mean
by "stubborn old war-horse".
Let's move out!
What are we going to do?
It's just as you predicted.
We can't rely on reinforcements, so we'll...
We'll use my old specialty, guerrilla tactics.
What do you think, Clamp?
The men would love it, sir!
So, they finally stopped.
What do you guys think you're doing?!
We don't have to be
on the White Base to fight.
We'll find a local Federation unit and...
You're going to abandon Bright?
Bright has Amuro with him.
Enough, Kai!
I've lost my reason to fight
aboard the White Base.
There's nothing anyone can do about it.
Hayato!
The Gallop goes in front of the Trojan Horse
and acts as a decoy, with Ghien's Zaku.
Then we come in from behind with the Cuis.
Hamon will take command of the Gallop.
Clamp and I will command
the first and second Cuis.
Got that?
Yes, sir!
All right. Mobilize the Gallop.
When we see the Trojan Horse, the Zaku
and Cuis will split off from the Gallop.
It's the Trojan Horse.
It's only moved 10 kilometers.
Excellent.
Zaku! Cuis! Prepare to launch from
the Gallop in 30 seconds.
All right, Hamon.
You can escape once we're on
the Trojan Horse.
You be careful too, dear.
You didn't have to hit me, Ryu!
That's right!
You can't force people to listen to you.
You guys won't understand unless you're hit!
What's that sound?
Huh?
Get down! We can't let them spot us.
That sound...
Must be the Gallop the prisoner mentioned.
It's headed for the White Base.
Ramba Ral's team.
You'll have to ask your own conscience
whether you'll come back or not.
Mr. Ryu!
Well, well...
Zaku, Ghien, launch!
Followed by the Cuis!
Launch!
Are we going?
Yes.
Is that all right?
Yeah.
It sure got chilly.
Mr. Kai...?
Huh? Oh, fine...
This wind, this sensation...
This is war!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
That boy...
Are you the pilot
of that white mobile suit, Gundam?
Such a nice boy.
Let's see how he fights.
Sayla! How close are they?!
I can't get an accurate estimate
at this station.
I've called for Oscar and Marker.
Prepare forward missiles!
Mirai! Get the power up on the main engine!
Yes, sir. Engine start, complete.
1 minute 20 seconds
until we can resume flight.
Sorry we slept in!
Open beam cannons on both sides!
The rear missiles too.
There's more than one enemy machine.
Roger! Open beam cannons!
Assessing the enemy!
Something in front of us.
Possibly the Gallop!
Can't see anything else due to the mountains.
Can the White Base ascend, sir?
Not yet! Open forward observation camera.
It's the Gallop! Entering firing range!
Fire main cannons!
They're here...!
Port-side guns!
What are you doing?!
There's a Zaku! Fire! Fire!
Bright, I'm launching in the Gundam.
Thanks, Sayla...
There's a Zaku on the left. Get some altitude
so you won't be a sitting duck.
I'm counting on you.
I'll do my best. Gundam, launching!
Fraw Bow, get Amuro out of the brig.
The door key is type 6E.
Do you understand?
Yes!
Hey, the White Base's buggies are driving
all the way over there!
They can't do anything over there!
What? Have Ryu and the others come back?
Over there! You can see them, Mr. Bright!
Mirai! Bring the forward deck level with
the mountain ledge on the starboard side.
Aye, sir.
Fraw Bow!
Amuro! Let's go!
The Gundam?
Ms. Sayla took it out.
You're manning the port-side machine guns.
All right!
Good luck!
Huh? What the hell are those?!
Looks like tanks...
You're right! Those are for commandos!
Maybe they're planning to storm us!
We're jumping onto the White Base!
Here we go!
The buggies made it!
Good.
Two tanks from behind!
What's that?
Commando tanks, called Cuis!
What? Commandos?
I'm sorry I took so long!
Ms. Sayla! Get further back before you aim!
Jump backwards!
All right!
Here he comes!
Got him!
Well done, Ms. Sayla!
The Trojan Horse is going to run!
Begin firing!
We're being attacked from behind!
Ryu! Kai! Anyone who can fight,
go to the rear!
We're going to halt the enemy's advance!
Marker! Oscar! Do you have sidearms?!
Yes, ma'am!
Unless they're trying to capture
the White Base...
...the Gallop would be hitting us harder!
That makes sense.
That man is coming...!
Attack!
Charge in where there's not as much fire!
Clamp team, let's go!
Don't let them into the White Base!
It's no good...
The Gundam's weapons are too powerful...
there's no way I can hit just the men.
You jerk! Go away! I hope you fall!
What's a little kid doing here?
Get back! Or you'll get hurt!
I'm telling you to get back!
Oscar and Marker! Take the bridge entrance!
Job John! To the front!
Yes!
All right! We can do it!
Hatch 78 has been breached!
What?!
Hurry! We're taking the sub-bridge!
If you were armed, I'd kill you!
Go hide somewhere!
It's you...!
The man from the restaurant...
You won because of that mobile suit!
Not because of your own strength!
Why you...!
Replace Sayla in the Gundam!
Use the Gundam to get the enemy
out of the second bridge.
How?!
Do it, even if the White Base takes damage.
Yes, sir!
Ms. Sayla!
Thank you, Amuro!
Sure!
Where's the enemy?!
The second bridge!
Okay!
Don't you think it's kind of strange...
...that they're all child soldiers?
Well, we're all short on personnel.
It's opening.
The enemy's here! The enemy!
Go straight!
No, you won't!
Cut the main bridge control circuits!
Yes, sir!
P-Princess...!
Is it really you, Princess?!
I'm certain of it. You must be Lady Artesia!
Have you forgotten me?
My father served under your father,
Sir Zeon Deikun.
I am Ramba Ral, son of Jimba Ral!
If you know that I'm Artesia...
why do you point that gun at me?!
What...? Then... what are you...
Sayla! Get back!
Ryu!
Ramba Ral, please stop!
Princess!
Amuro, can you hear me?!
They've taken the second bridge!
Destroy it!
Roger!
C... Contact Hamon...
Sir! I have the frequency.
You men retreat. The mission's a failure!
Dear... ?!
I'm sorry, Hamon.
Destroy the Trojan Horse with the Gallop.
In the middle of a fight,
Ramba Ral forgot to fight.
But Lady Artesia...
What's happened?!
It's that mobile suit, Gundam.
To think that my opponents
were all less than half my age...
How ironic.
You have fought splendidly.
But now you'll see the fate of a soldier.
I want you to watch closely.
Ral...
Ms. Hamon!
Ramba Ral is dead!
Stop it now!
Eject the bridge!
Still nothing from the lieutenant?
Yes.
That was the last.
I see.
Ramba Ral...
And Hamon...
Quietly.
Carry him carefully.
Hamon carries on the objective
of the fallen warrior, Ramba Ral.
With so few weapons at her disposal...
...will Hamon be the one
to finally bring down Gundam?
In the midst of this crisis,
Ryu Jose's Core Fighter appears...
...to attack Hamon.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Sorrow and Hatred.
Next Time
Sorrow and Hatred
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...